GALEN KUSAKABE

Phone: (206)-660-2076

E-mail: **GTKusakabe@GMail.com**

www.linkedin.com/in/galen-kusakabe-4118665

SUMMARY

Customer service oriented Windows System Engineer with 20+ years of technical support experience with a willingness to learn. A good problem solver with an attention to detail while in a fast paced environment, supporting critical situations in all corporate levels. With my experience as a Service Desk technician, Desktop Technician and Windows System Engineer, I feel I can bring a wealth of knowledge to your position.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Nordstrom Information Technology, Seattle, WA

April 1997 – March 2021

Windows System Engineer

December 2018 - March 2021

- Provide Support of daily issues and requests that are assigned to the department in a thorough and timely manner to meet customers and department service level agreement
- Using Configuration Manager, created and deployed packaged applications and monthly patches,
 created queries/collections, and worked to resolve deployment failures
- Build and maintain Remote Desktop Servers, standalone and clusters to provide a working platform for our business partners
- Build and maintain company File/Print servers for the company
- Use standard tools DHCP, DNS, Group Policy, Active Directory and Azure Active Directory
- Use PowerShell to streamline processes
- Work closely with other teams to provide a seamless resolution for their incident/request
- Proficient with ServiceNow, Jira, and confluence applications and ITIL Certified

Client Technology Conferencing

Conferencing Engineer

May 2016 - December 2018

- Provided Support of daily issues and request to are assigned to the department in thorough and timely manner to meet customers and department SLA
- Build and Support the company Cisco Telepresence infrastructure for the company Video Conferencing Rooms, Telepresence Management Server, and Cisco Expressway servers
- Built and managed the On-Prem BlueJeans Accelerator Servers

References available upon request

- Managed the BlueJeans Relay server for meeting integration with Office 365
- Managed the BlueJeans on-boarding and license management for the company
- Performed RFI/RFP to test various Video Conferencing Platforms to assure we were using the highest quality platform
- Provided on-hand's support of Video Conferencing equipment both backend and user facing

Nordstrom Information Technology, Seattle, WA

October 2014 - May 2016

Windows System Engineer

- Provide Support of daily issues and requests that are assigned to the department in a thorough and timely manner to meet customers and department service level agreement
- Using Configuration Manager, created and deployed packaged applications and monthly patches, created queries/collections, and worked to resolve deployment failures
- Build and maintain Remote Desktop Servers, standalone and clusters to provide a working platform for our business partners
- Build and maintain company File/Print servers for the company
- Use standard tools DHCP, DNS, Group Policy, Active Directory and Azure Active Directory
- Use PowerShell to streamline processes
- Work closely with other teams to provide a seamless resolution for their incident/request
- Proficient with ServiceNow, Jira, and confluence applications and ITIL Certified

Corporate Technology Support, Sr Technician

September 1998 – October 2014

- Executive Support for Nordstrom family and provided an elevated level of support for Executive
 Team Tier 1 support for building servers, network, conference room technology and phone support
- Provided technical support for the corporate offices, Nordstrom hangar (Seattle), and photo studio supporting the servers, printers, monitors, personal computers, flight specific applications, software
- Escalation Technician for CTS and regional technicians to troubleshoot and work issues that require additional attention while documenting and sharing issues/resolution with the team
- Telephony support for the corporate campus, creating and managing voice profiles for our corporate users on the Avaya Communications Manager
- Technical SME, coaching and training on various topics and issues
- Supported the Nordstrom Hangar, providing remote support for the Servers, pc's, and Telephony,
 along with Flight specific applications.

 Reviewed All Department tickets (Incidents/Request) to ensure proper closure for accurate reporting.

Customer Service Group/Helpdesk

April 1997 - August 1998

- Provided Tier 1 phone support for company end-users for all PC, application, and mobile issues that come about
- Troubleshoot issues and document processes for our knowledge base for future reference
- Work with escalation groups to ensure smooth transition for incident, as needed
- Trained new technicians to the Help Desk

EDUCATION

University of Washington, Seattle, WA

Bachelor of Science in Forest Management

OTHER INTERESTS

Enjoys golfing, skiing, tennis, and watching Seattle area sports with my family